Guide to the Ramus family papers and photographs 1978.174
Brooklyn Historical Society
Ramus family papers and photographs
circa 1840-1920
Brooklyn Historical Society
Ramus, Louis
Ramus, Esther
Ramus, Angelo
Ramus family
1978.174
0.7 Linear Feet in 7 folders, one photograph box, and one oversize folder.
The Ramus family papers and photographs contain citizenship papers, estate documents, wills, land and property documents, correspondence and ephemera, and genealogical notes along with photographs of immediate and extended Ramus Family members.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Louis Ramus, date unknown. The papers were formally accessioned in 1978. The accession papers list a variant spelling of the last name, written as "Ramos."
Existence and Location of Copies
Item-level description and digital versions of images from the collection are available for searching via the online image database under the object ID prefix V1978.174.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series by type. Series 1 comprises the family's papers and Series 2 is photographs. Within each series, materials are arranged by type and ordered chronologically.
Biographical note
Isaac Ramus (circa 1805-1876) was a retail dealer in hosiery and undergarments with a store located at 385 Canal Street in Manhattan. He married Esther Baruth (1810-1886) in 1830. They emigrated from London and lived at 214 Dean Street in Brooklyn. Their son Angelo (circa 1834-1860) moved to San Francisco in adulthood, and died there at the age of 26 from yellow fever. Their other son Louis Ramus married Hannah Levy, who died at 36 years of age.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The collection's digital surrogates should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
Scope and Contents
The Ramus family papers and photographs contain citizenship papers, estate documents, wills, land and property documents, correspondence and ephemera, and genealogical notes pertaining to the Ramus family of Brooklyn. Photographs depict immediate family as well as extended family and in-laws. The majority of documents, ephemera, and photographs pertain to Louis Ramus and Hanna Levy's children, Ira and Julian, Adele Schwartz and parents, Ira Silverberg and family, as well as some of Hannah's family.
Deeds; Citizenship papers; Wills; Estate records; Genealogies; Families -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Genealogy; Black-and-white prints (photographs); Daguerreotypes (photographs); Tintypes (prints); Cabinet photographs; Photograph albums; Cartes-de-visite (card photographs); Studio portraits; Portraits; Ambrotypes (photographs); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Boerum Hill (New York, N.Y.); Furniture; Furniture industry and trade -- New York (State) -- New York; Licenses; Certificates; Receipts (financial records); Ramus, Julian; Ramus, Mariah; Ramus, Isaac; Ramus, Louis
- Series 1: Papers
  Scope and Contents
  The Ramus family papers include citizenship papers, estate documents, wills, land and property documents, correspondence and ephemera pertaining to the Ramus family of Brooklyn. Genealogical notes are also available in the collection.
  - Citizenship documents, 1840-1855 (Box A0034, Box OS-9)
  - Correspondence, 1850-1861 (Box A0034)
  - Internal Revenue licenses and receipts, 1863-1868 (Box A0034)
  - Finance and property records, 1867-1898 (Box A0034, Box OS-9)
  - Ephemera and genealogy notes, circa 1875-1904 (Box A0034, Box OS-9)
  - Estate papers, 1876, 1886 (Box A0034)
- Series 2: Photographs
  The collection is organized by photographic object type and includes 29 cabinet cards, 8 tintypes, 3 daguerrotypes, 3 ambrotypes, and 2 photographic postcards, as well as one bound album with metal clasp comprised of cartes-de-visite, tintypes and 1 photographic print.
  Photograph albums; Cartes-de-visite (card photographs); Photographic postcards; Families -- New York (State); Tintypes (prints); Ambrotypes (photographs); Cabinet photographs; Daguerreotypes (photographs); Ramus family
  - Daguerreotypes, 1840 and 1860 (Box 1, Item V1978.174.32-34)
  - Photograph Album, 1848 and 1917; 1850-1910; SCRAP.2009.10 (Box 1)
  - Ambrotypes, 1850 and 1865 (Box 1, Item V1978.174.36-38)
  - Cartes-de-visite, 1850 and 1870 (Box 1)
  - Tintypes, 1855 and 1920 (Box 1)
  - Cabinet Cards, 1870 and 1920 (Box 1, Item V1978.174.1-25, 85, Box A0034, Item V1978.174.26-28)
  - Photographic Postcards, 1905 and 1920 (Box 1)